

Location Sofia, Bulgaria

Phone

+359 898 238 883

Email

nikola.n.lazarov@outlook.com

Website

https://nikolalazarov.com

YouTube Channel

https://youtube.com/@nltech1

Nikola Lazarov

Senior Front-End Developer | Content Creator | Technical Entrepreneur

Summary

Senior Front-End Developer with 5+ years at Progress, where I've progressed from intern to senior role since 2018. My favorite part of software engineering is collaborating with colleagues to invent elegant solutions that integrate seamlessly into existing architectures, focusing on minimal, reliable code.

I create YouTube educational content on the latest software engineering technologies. Teaching others forces me to truly understand concepts deeply - I find that explaining something clearly is the best way to learn it myself.

I founded Budget Warden to combine my interest in responsible personal finance with my technical values - building fast, native software that actually works well.

Experience

Progress Software

Senior Front-End Developer

March 2020 - Present

Intern Front-End Developer

March 2018 - September 2018

Budget Warden

Founder & Software Developer

May 2024 - Present

Education

American University in Bulgaria

Bachelor of Arts Computer Science & Information Systems March 2016 - 2020

Skills

- Computer Science Fundamentals Data Structures, Algorithms,
 Design Patterns, Object-Oriented, Functional Programming and Data-Oriented Design
- I use JavaScript/TypeScript, Rust and C++ daily. I have previous experience with C#, Java, PHP and other C-based languages.
- Operating Systems, Containers, Database Technologies (Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB), database design and normalization
- Internet Protocol stack, HTTP(s), RESTful API design
- Multi-year experience with web technologies, web accessibility (WCAG standards) and performance optmization techniques